Opeoluwa Olatunbosun Rodemade

18 Gbeleyi Street, Alakuko, Alagbado, Lagos State, Nigeria; Gender: Male Nationality: Nigerian; Contact: +2348155284570; Email: ropeoluwa@hotmail.com.

Career Summary: I am an Electrical Engineer with expertise in PLC programming, power system tools, and Laser machining. As a professional engineer, I work towards minimizing project downtime, and optimizing the overall equipment effectiveness through the lean philosophy of operation.

Work Experience

UniTeS Cisco Networking Academy

Virtual Internship Program

09.2020 - 11.2020

- Introduction to Cybersecurity
- Use of ethical Hacking Tools.
- Network configuration and connection.
- Use of Wireshark for network monitoring.
- Deployment of network encryption.

Yachthafenresidenz Hohe Duene (5 Star Hotel), Rostock, Germany

Support Staff 01.2017 – 03.2018

- My tasks include serving the guests and hoteliers.
- Strategically designing the conference rooms for conference meetings
- Organising the conference hall for exhibitions.
- Strategically organising the conference hall for major company's annual general meetings.

Nigerian Television Authority, Imeko, Ogun State

Engineer II 05.2013 – 3.2016

- I supervised the work orders for programs in the control room.
- I was responsible for the maintenance log, proper shutdown and start-up of the transmitter.
- I was responsible for the catalogue of spare parts and reduced equipment downtime by 25% through close observation for preventive maintenance.

Auchi Polytechnic Consults Ltd

Production Engineer (NYSC)

11.2009 - 11.2010

- I supervised production staff to meet the shift production target.
- I ensured all production staff wear personal protective equipment (PPEs) to ensure safety at work.
- I achieved 40% reduction in shutdown time by providing adequate corrective maintenance and close observation of the plant machinery.

Reckitt Benckiser Nigeria Ltd

Industrial Intern 05.2006 – 04.2007

- I worked with the factory engineers to ensure proper maintenance of the factory machinery.
- I was responsible for the delivery log of diesels for the factory generator.
- I performed weekly checks on the production floors to ensure HSE compliance.
- I performed routine SCADA control of machines at remote locations.

Education

University of Ilorin, Nigeria	
Master of Business Administration	01/2019 – 03/2021
University of Sunderland, United Kingdom	
Bachelor's degree in Electrical and Electronic Engineering (First Class)	09/2011 – 06/2012
Federal Polytechnic Ilaro, Ogun State, Nigeria	
Higher National Diploma in Electrical Engineering (Distinction)	09/2007 – 07/2009
Ordinary National Diploma in Electrical Engineering (Upper Credit)	09/2004 – 05/2006

Job Related Skills

I am proficient in SIFT Image processing; HVDC/HVAC Systems; PLC/SCADA Programming; AutoCAD; PSCAD/EMTDC; Rapid Prototyping; C++, ANSYS; MATLAB/Python Programming; and MS Office Suite. I have had training sessions on 5s, Total Productive Maintenance (TPM pillars), as well as trainings on Health, Safety and the environment (HSE).

Intensive IT Training

Zuri Training & Ingressive for Good (I4G)

Frontend Development (HTML/CSS, JavaScript)

Professional Membership

Member (MIET)

The Institution of Engineering and Technology

01.2014 till date